Kendall Rundquist

Front End Developer with expertise in adjacent roles

Profile

Passionate Front End Developer with over two years of experience turning ideas into reality using React and JavaScript. A few highlights of past experience include:

- Developing a fully redesigned electric vehicle marketing website
- Developing a custom website editor to alleviate pressure on developers to maintain website content In my next role, I would like to continue building on my experience with React and JavaScript while learning new technologies and skills

Skills

Languages (TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS)

Frameworks & Libraries (Next.js, React, GraphQL, Strapi, Rest API, Jest)

Tooling & CI/CD (Node.js, NPM, Git, Docker)

Professional Experience

Software Engineer

Oct 2020 - May 2023 | Austin, TX

General Motors

- Developed a functional POC of GM's Electric Vehicle Marketing Platform with only ambiguous requirements using React, Strapi, and NextJS
- Redesigned and maintained Chevrolet's Electric Vehicle webpages using React and Material UI leading to increased customer awareness and interest in GM products
- Improved Lighthouse web quality score to over 90 out of 100 in the majority of categories
- Developed a hybrid WYSIWYG editor that allowed for easier creation and maintenance of GM's marketing websites using React, Styled Components, and React Query. Enabled the reduction of developer time spent on site maintenance by 75%.
- Designed and built lead generation forms to track interest for multiple vehicles and product reveals, boosting lead generation by 50%

Product Owner

Apr 2018 - Oct 2020 | Austin, TX

General Motors

- Led cross-functional discussions with various stakeholders for a major redesign of the Online Service Scheduling application reducing time to schedule appointments by 30%
- Devised multi-year strategic feature roadmaps for the OSS application
- Designed user stories based on business and customer requirements

Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET)

Jun 2015 - Apr 2018 | Austin, TX

General Motors

- Initiated and led the automation effort for several web applications. Efforts led to improved turnaround time, higher regression coverage, and more accurate reporting in TFS for
- Optimized the Online Service Scheduling regression test suite to reduce duplicate and outdated tests and streamline regression testing resulting in a 25% reduced testing time
- Trained new members on testing and automation best practices increasing all-around testing productivity

Education

B.B.A. in Management Information Systems

May 2015

Baylor University

Certificates

- Full Stack JavaScript TechDegree ☑